{
    "id": "ea85e1196dca4f98aef3b87579962946",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It ………………………. not take me more than 10 minutes to get ready.",
            "description": "Use does with it. Has is used with the past participle forms of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "does",
                "do",
                "has"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… leave now.",
            "description": "In the simple present tense we make negatives and questions with do and does. ",
            "answers": [
                "Don't",
                "Not"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… at once.",
            "description": "The simple present is used in imperative sentences.",
            "answers": [
                "Leave",
                "Left",
                "Leaving"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "When I was young I …………………….. walk 10 miles in an hour.",
            "description": "Use could to talk about past ability.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "will"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They ………………………… live in a caravan.",
            "description": "Would cannot refer to past states only used to can refer to past states. ",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "used to",
                "are used to"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The old woman ………………………… spend hours talking to herself.",
            "description": "Would and used to can both be used to talk about past habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "used to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Once upon a time, there ………………………. a pretty girl.",
            "description": "Use past tenses in story telling.",
            "answers": [
                "lives",
                "lived",
                "lives"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I cannot let go ………………………. him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "of",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "They gave ………………………. without any resistance.",
            "description": "To give in is to surrender. ",
            "answers": [
                "out",
                "in",
                "up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A powerful earthquake ……………………….. the city yesterday.",
            "description": "Use the simple past to say when something happened. ",
            "answers": [
                "has ravaged",
                "ravages",
                "ravaged"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………. them before.",
            "description": "The present perfect is more common with before. ",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "have met",
                "meet"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I didn’t realize that I ……………………… a mistake.",
            "description": "When the main verb is the past tense, use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "am making",
                "was making",
                "have made"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}